ASHLEY COOK ASHLEY COOK@MAIL.COM 07960213542

PROFILE

A junior web/front end developer with 8 years previous experience working within the financial, housing and recruitment industries. A personable, passionate, calm and flexible person who will go above and beyond his duties with effective negotiating and creative skills. Now seeking a challenge to work in Web development which is his ultimate passion and he wants to progress his career in this industry.

SKILLS

- Web development technologies: HTML,CSS,JavaScript, Node js, GIT, bootstrap, jquery, Tailwind. React is
- Customer Service experience
- Credit recovery skills
- Sales Ability
- Proficient in MS Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Publisher)
- Basic knowledge of SQL, CRM and call media.

CAREER HISTORY

November 2022 to Current

EdX Front End Development Bootcamp

- · Learning the fundamentals of web development and different frameworks
- 12 personal projects built using HTML, Git, CSS, JavaScript, Node js, Jquery, React, Bootstrap and Tailwind CSS- 94% current pass mark.
- 2 group projects using all technologies mentioned previously. Project 1- 95% pass mark.
- Currently studying towards a certification in Tensorflow (Machine Learning) and Python.

November 2019 to November 2022, Client Liaison Officer, STA International

- Managing a portfolio of 12 Client accounts in the educational sector
- Recovering debt from Account Portfolio: assessing individual account funds and implementing a suitable and affordable payment plan and building a good relationship with the customer to ensure that they adhere to the plan.
- Liasing with clients and preparing accounts for legal action
- Reviewing cases for further action, target based kpis based on revenue
- Management of emails and internal web messages to clients

February 2018 - September 2019, Customer Service Advisor, CLARION HOUSING

- Receive and process Housing queries relating to rent, ASB reports and general enquiries navigating the call through to customer satisfaction.
- Capture and record relevant sales and technical data on the system.
- Deal with complaints/issues/concerns in a timely manner and ensure the customers journey is smooth whilst always working to achieve company KPI's.
- Successfully achieved set targets each month assessed on adherence, quality and phone time.
- Management of emails and dissemination of documents.
- Advise customer on payment and account management in a professional manner.

April 2017-Febuary 2018, Contract Resource Consultant, HANSON REGAN I.T RECRUITMENT

- Sourcing and generating potential SAP candidates for key accounts using the (Boolean), in house CRM system, LinkedIn and other.
- Collating and developing potential candidates using the company qualifying process.
- Pre-screen candidates on the telephone prior to interview.
- Provide feedback after interview, negotiate salary and start time.
- Achieved first placement of candidate within 4 weeks of starting the role.
- Utilize potential candidates' database outside SAP such as LinkedIn to generate interest.

September 2016 -April 2017, Collections Agent, CABOT CREDIT MANAGEMENT

- Recovering debt from Account Portfolio: assessing individual account funds and implementing a suitable and affordable payment plan and building a good relationship with the customer to ensure that they adhere to the plan.
- Signposting vulnerable customers to the relevant authorities/charities for further assistance.
- Successfully achieved monthly target resulting in a bonus.
- Successfully passed the CAI test by 98%. Holder of a certificate on the Institute of Customer Service.
- Updating and maintaining customer accounts on income and expenditure investigating irregularities and discrepancies.
- Deal with disputes and complaints prior to escalation.

Travelled Within Europe May 2016 - September 2016

September 2012 - April May 2016 Collections Specialist/Supervisor, VANQUIS BANK

- Payment Channel Specialist promoted to Assistant Supervisor
- Accountable to recover funds from Vanquis Cardholders adhering to the FCA guidelines.
- Communicating with customers via digital channels in regards outstanding balance on accounts
- Provide professional decision making regarding the customers financial accounts.
- Addressing complaints and general queries with a view a resolution.
- Update and maintain customer records of daily activities.
- Supervise various teams in the absence of management i.e. annual leave, sick etc.
- Analysing performance related data to feedback to the agents with a view to improve KPI's.
- Reviewing calls to ensure regulatory FCA guidelines are adhered to.
- Training new agents in their new role.
- Participated in projects to improve customer satisfaction; new processes and motivating teams.

OTHER ROLES

- October 2010- June 2012, Anglian Home Improvements, Telephone canvasser.
- April 2010- October 2010, Weatherseal Home Improvements, Telephone Canvasser
- February 2008-November 2011, Metrorod Canterbury, Part Time Drainage Engineer

EDUCATION

September 2007- June 2009, South Kent College

National Diploma in Music Technology- BBC

September2002-2007, Wrotham School

- AS LEVEL- Geography and Religious Studies- E
- GCSE'S: A-C- Math's, English, Geography, Media Studies, Religious Studies, History INTERESTS

FLYING, WATCHING FOOTBALL, FITNESS. DJING

REFERENCES

Available on request